{
    "quiz": {
        "sport": {
            "q1": {
                "question": "Which team won the English Premier League in the 2020-2021 season?",
                "options": [
					"Manchester United",
					"Manchester City",
					"Liverpool",
					"Chelsea"                    
                ],
                "answer": "Manchester City"
            },
			"q2": {
                "question": "Who is the all-time leading goal scorer in the English Premier League?",
                "options": [
				    "Wayne Rooney",
                    "Alan Shearer",
                    "Thierry Henry",
                    "Cristiano Ronaldo"
                ],
                "answer": "Alan Shearer"
            },
			"q3": {
                "question": "Who is the highest run-scorer in the history of Pakistan cricket?",
                "options": [
                    "Inzamam-ul-Haq",
                    "Javed Miandad",
                    "Muhammad Yousaf",
                    "Babar Azam"
                ],
                "answer": "Muhammad Yousaf"
            },
			"q4": {
                "question": "Who holds the record for the highest individual score by a Pakistani batsman in Test cricket?",
                "options": [
                    "Hanif Mohammad",
                    "Younis Khan",
                    "Azhar Ali",
                    "Inzamam-ul-Haq"
                ],
                "answer": "Hanif Mohammad"
            },
			"q5,": {
                "question": "Which team has won the most English Premier League titles?",
                "options": [
                    "Manchester United",
                    "Liverpool",
                    "Arsenal",
                    "Chelsea"
                ],
                "answer": "Manchester United"
            },
			"q6": {
                "question": "Which Pakistani cricketer has taken the most wickets in Test matches?",
                "options": [
                    "Waqar Younis",
                    "Wasim Akram",
                    "Mushtaq Ahmad",
                    "Saqlain Mushtaq"
                ],
                "answer": "Wasim Akram"
            },
			"q7": {
                "question": "Who holds the record for the most assists in a single English Premier League season?",
                "options": [
                    "Mesut Ozil",
                    "Kevin De Bruyne",
                    "Thierry Henry",
                    "Frank Lampard"
                ],
                "answer": "Kevin De Bruyne"
            },
			"q8": {
                "question": "Who is the current captain of the Pakistan national cricket team in One-Day Internationals (ODIs)?",
                "options": [
                    "Babar Azam",
                    "Shoaib Malik",
                    "Muhammad Rizwan",
                    "Sarfaraz Ahmed"
                ],
                "answer": "Babar Azam"
            },
			"q9": {
                "question": "Which club has the highest number of consecutive English Premier League titles?",
                "options": [
                    "Manchester United",
                    "Arsenal",
                    "Chelsea",
                    "Manchester City"
                ],
                "answer": "Manchester United"
            },
			"q10": {
                "question": "Which Pakistani cricketer has the highest number of centuries in T20 International cricket?",
                "options": [
                    "Shoaib Malik",
                    "Ahmed Shehzad",
                    "Babar Azam",
                    "Muhammad Hafeez"
                ],
                "answer": "Babar Azam"
            }
        },
        "engineering": {
            "q1": {
                "question": "What is the determinant of a 3x3 matrix?",
                "options": [
                    "It is always 1",
                    "It is always 0",
                    "It can be any real number",
                    "It depends on the entries of the matrix"
                ],
                "answer": "It depends on the entries of the matrix"
            },
            "q2": {
                "question": "What is the median of a dataset?",
                "options": [
                    "The most frequently occurring value in the dataset.",
                    "The arithmetic average of all the values in the dataset.",
                    "The middle value when the dataset is arranged in ascending order.",
                    "The difference between the highest and lowest values in the dataset."
                ],
                "answer": "The middle value when the dataset is arranged in ascending order."
            },
			"q3": {
                "question": "What does it mean for a matrix to be invertible?",
                "options": [
                    "The matrix has no inverse.",
                    "The matrix has a unique inverse.",
                    "The matrix has inifinitely many inverses.",
                    "The matrix is a diagnol matrix."
                ],
                "answer": "The matrix has a unique inverse."
            },
            "q4": {
                "question": "What is the purpose of a microcontroller in an electronic system?",
                "options": [
                    "To control the power supply of the system.",
                    "To provide communication interfaces for external devices.",
                    "To execute a program and perform specific tasks or functions.",
                    "To regulate the temperature of the electronic components."
                ],
                "answer": "To execute a program and perform specific tasks or functions."
            },
			"q5": {
                "question": "What is the purpose of a standard deviation in statistics?",
                "options": [
                    "To measure the spread or variability of data points in a dataset.",
                    "To determine the central tendency of a dataset.",
                    "To identify outliers in a dataset.",
                    "To calculate the probability of an event occurring."
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
            "q6": {
                "question": "In a system of linear equations, when does the solution exist?",
                "options": [
                    "The solution always exists.",
                    "The solution exists if and only if the system is inconsistent.",
                    " The solution exists if and only if the system is homogeneous.",
                    "The solution exists if and only if the system is consistent and has a unique solution."
                ],
                "answer": "The solution exists if and only if the system is consistent and has a unique solution."
            },
			"q7": {
                "question": "What is image segmentation in digital image processing?",
                "options": [
                    "The process of enhancing the resolution of an image.",
                    "The process of converting a color image to grayscale.",
                    "The process of dividing an image into meaningful regions or objects.",
                    "The process of reducing the size of an image without significant loss of quality."
                ],
                "answer": "The process of dividing an image into meaningful regions or objects."
            },
            "q8": {
                "question": "What is the difference between a microcontroller and a microprocessor?",
                "options": [
                    "Microcontrollers are used in embedded systems, while microprocessors are used in personal computers.",
                    "Microcontrollers have built-in memory and peripherals, while microprocessors require external components.",
                    "Microcontrollers have higher processing power than microprocessors.",
                    "Microprocessors are typically smaller in size compared to microcontrollers."
                ],
                "answer": "Microcontrollers have built-in memory and peripherals, while microprocessors require external components."
            },
			"q9": {
                "question": "What is the purpose of a low-pass filter in image processing?",
                "options": [
                    "To enhance the high-frequency components of an image.",
                    "To remove noise or high-frequency details from an image.",
                    "To convert a color image to grayscale.",
                    "To detect and enhance edges in an image."
                ],
                "answer": "To remove noise or high-frequency details from an image."
            },
            "q10": {
                "question": "What does the p-value represent in hypothesis testing?",
                "options": [
                    "The likelihood of making a Type II error.",
                    "The level of significance for rejecting the null hypothesis.",
                    "The strength of the relationship between two variables.",
                    "The probability of observing the test statistic or a more extreme value, assuming the null hypothesis is true."
                ],
                "answer": "The probability of observing the test statistic or a more extreme value, assuming the null hypothesis is true."
            }
        }
    }
}